Finding Aid for the Dorothy Bethurum Loomis Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series IV Other Academics' Writings
  - Helaine Newstead, "Some Observations of King Herla and the Herlething" (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Canterbury Tales: Early Manuscripts and Relative Popularity", January, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "Chaucer's Canterbury Tales: Aesthetic Design in Stories of the First Day", April, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Crucial Passage in Five of the Canterbury Tales: A Study in Irony and Symbol", July, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Development of the Canterbury Tales", July, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Earliest Plan of the 'Canterbury Tales,'" (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "Morality as a Comic Motif in the Canterbury Tales", January, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Plan of the Canterbury Pilgrimage", September, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "Relationship between the Physicians's Tale and Parson's Tale", February, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Role of the Narrator in the 'Parlement of Foules,'", February, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "Significance of a Day in 'Troilus and Criseyde,'" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Significance of Chaucer's Revisions of Troilus and Criseyde", August, 1957 (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Charles A. Owen, Jr., "The Twenty-Nine Pilgrims and the Three Priests", May, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Howard R. Patch, "Mediavel Romance in England, A Study of the Sources and Analogues of the noncyclic Metrical Romances (Laura A. Hibbard)", undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Howard R. Patch, "Reivew: Chaucer: A Critical Appreciation (Paull F. Baum)", January, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Howard Rollin Patch, "Some Elements in Mediaeval Descriptions of the Otherworld" (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Howard R. Patch, "Three Medieval Ideas", October 1939-July 1940 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer and Le Roman de Troyle et de Criseida", October, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer and Les Cronicles of Nicholas Trevet" (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer and the Hand that Fed Him", October, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer and the Holy Cross of Bromholm", May, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer and the Pillars of Hercules", January, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer and the Visconti Libraries", September, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Chaucer's Claudian", July, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Robert Armstrong Pratt, "The Classical Lamentations in the Nun's Priest's Tale" (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Conjectures Regarding Chaucer's Manuscript of the Teseida", October, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "The Development of the Wife of Bath", undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Robert Armstrong Pratt, "Geoffrey Caucer, ESQ., and Sir John Hawkwood", September, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Robert Armstrong Pratt, "The Importance of Manuscripts for the Study of Medieval Education, as Revealed by the Learning of Chaucer" (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Jankyn's Books of Wikked Wyves: Medieval Antimatrimonial Propaganda in the Universities" (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Robert Armstrong Pratt, "A Note on Chaucer's Lollius", March, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "The Order of the Canterbury Tales", December, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Saint Jerome in Jankyn's Book of Wikked Wyves", Fall, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Three Old French Sources of the Nonnes Preestes Tale (Part I and II)", July-October, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Robert A. Pratt, "Was Robyn the Miller's Youth Misspent?", January, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Alain Renoir, "Attitudes Toward Women in Lydgate's Poetry", undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Alain Renoir, "Descriptive Technique in Sir Gawain and the Green Knight", undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "The Burden in Carols", January, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "The Fraternity of Drinkers", January, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "A Gawain Epigone", May, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "God Amende Wykkyd Cownscell (1464)" (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "A Late Fifteenth Century Love Lyric", March, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "Levation Prayers in Middle English Verse", November, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "Middle English Carols as Processional Hymns", October, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "The Middle English Carol Corpus: Some Additions", March, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "Middle English Versions of 'Criste qui lux es et dies,'", January, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "A Political Action Poem, 1463", April, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "Theo Stemmler, Die englischen Liebesgedichte des MS. Harley 2253" (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Rossell Hope Robbins, "Two New Carols", January, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - John Hawley Roberts, "The Nine Worthies", undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Ruth E. Roberts, "Review: The Education of the Hero in Arthurian Romance (Cosman)" (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - D. J. A. Ross, "Alexander and the Faithless Lady: A Submarine Adventure" (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - David J. A. Ross, "Allegory and Romance on a Medieval French Marriage Casket" (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - D. J. A. Ross, "Gautier Del Hum, an Historical Element in the 'Chanson de Roland'?", July, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - D. J. A. Ross, "Olympias and the Serpent" (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - J. C. Russell, "Hereford and Arabic Science in England about 1175-1200", July, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - J. C. Russell, "Notes on the Biography of Saint Edmund of Abingdon", July, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - J. C. Russell, "The Patrons of The Owl and the Nightingale", April, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Hans Sauer, "Zur Überlieferung und Anlage von Erzbischof Wulfstans 'Handbunch,'", undated (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Margaret R. Scherer, "About the Round Table" (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Anglistik", September, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Bonet, Gower, and Polish Jurists on the Rights of Non-Believers" (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Chaucer's Doctrine of Kings and Tyrants", April, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Chaucer's Prose Rhythms", June, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Realism and Convention in Medieval Literature" (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Rhetorical Doctrine and Some Aspects of Medieval Narrative" (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "Thomas Usk as Translator" (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Margaret Schlauch, "The Two Styles of Thomas Usk" (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - J. Burke Severs, "Author's Revision in Block C of the Canterbury Tales", July, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - J. Burke Severs, "Did Chaucer Rearrange the Clerk's Envoy?", November, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - J. Burke Severs, "Is the Manciple's Tale a Success?", January, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Theodore Silverstein, "Andreas, Plato, and the Arabs Remarks on Some Recent Accounts of Courtly Love", November, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Charles S. Singleton, "In Exitu Israel de Aegypto", undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Eugene E. Slaughter, "Chaucer's Pandarus: Virtuous Uncle and Friend", April, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - C. H. Slover, "Glastonbury Abbey and the Fusing of English Literary Culture", April, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Clark Harris Slover, "William of Malmesbury and the Irish" (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Roland M. Smith, "The Limited Vision of Saint Bernard", January, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Roland M. Smith, "Price, the Equatorie of the Planetis/Osgood, Index to the Variorum Spenser", July, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - H. M. Smyser, "Charlemagne and Roland and the Auchinleck MS.", July, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - H. M. Smyser, "Chaucer's Two-Mile Pilgrimage", March, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - H. M. Smyser, "The Domestic Background of Troilus and Criseyde", April, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - H. M. Smyser, "How Shall the Undergraduate Read Chaucer? Some Suggestions", April, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - H. M. Smyser, "The List of Norman Names in the Auchinleck MS. (Battle Abbey Roll)" (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - H. M. Smyser, "The Middle English and Old Norse Story of Olive", March, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - H. M. Smyser, "Olive Again", December, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - H. M. Smyser, "Review: the Saga of Thorgils and Haflidi (Halldor Hermannsson, ed.)", July, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - H. M. Smyser, "Review: Sir Orgeo (A. J. Bliss, ed), "January (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - H. M. Smyser, "Review: Sire Gauvain et le Chevalier Vert (Emile Pons)", January, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Arpad Steiner, "The Date of Composition of Mandeville's Travels", undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Gardiner Stillwell, "Chaucer's Eagles and their Choice on February 14", October, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Gardiner Stillwell, "Convention and Individuality in Chaucer's Complaint of Mars", January, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Gardiner Stillwell, "Unity and Comedy in Chaucer's Parliament of Foules", October, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Allen Tate, "Mere Literature and the Lost Traveller", July 17, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - J. S. P. Tatlock, "Has Chaucer's Wretched Engendering Been Found?," Germaine Dempster, "Did Chaucer Write An Holy Medytacion?," Carleton Brown, "An Affirmative Reply", May, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - J. S. P. Tatlock, "Reivew: Andreas Capellanus, The Art of Courtly Love (J. J. Parry, ed. and Transl.)", April, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Florence E. Teager, "Notes on Chaucer and the Rhetoricians" (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Lynn Thorndike, "Renaissance or Prenaissance", January, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Lynn Thorndike, "Sanitation, Baths and Street Cleaning in the Middle Ages and Renaissance" (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Hope Traver, "The Four Daughters of God: A Mirror of Changing Doctrine", undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Anglicanism and Anthropology: C. S. Lewis and John Speirs", undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Arthurian Romance and International Folktale Method", February, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "The Boundaries of Language and Rhetoric: the English Curriculum", May, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "The Devil in the Ark (AaTh 825)" (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "The Equine Subconscious in Ireland", April, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "European Folk Tales (laurits Bodker, Christina Hole, and G. d'Aronco, ed.)", July, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "The Flood Narrative in the Junius Manuscript and in Baltic Literature" (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Folk Literature: An Operational Definition", July-September, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Folklore, Myth, and Ritual" (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "The Linguistic Component of Onomastics", September, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Obituary: C. Grant Loomis", April-June, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Book Review: a Critical History of Old English Literature (Stanley B. Greenfield)", fall, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: Chacuer and the Fifteenth Century (H. S. Bennett)", April, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Frances Lee Utley, "Review: The Encyclopedia of Witchcraft and Demonology (Rossell Hope Robbins)" (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - F. L. Utley, "Review: Fabliaux: Ribald Tales from the Old French (R. Hellman and R. O' Gorman)," "Review: The Northmen Talk: A Choice of Tales from Iceland (J. Simpson, ed and Trans.)", July, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: Fundamental of Folk Literature (George W. Boswell and J. Russell Reaver)", April, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: The Legend of the Wandering Jew", November, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - F. L. Utley, "Review: A Mirror of Chaucer's World (R. S. Loomis)", July, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: Moral Philosopher and Friend of Chaucer (John Gower)", October, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: the narreme in the Medieval Romance Epic", March, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: Peasant Customs and Savage Myths: Selections from the British Folklorists", August, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Review: Quest of Seth for the Oil of Life (Esther Casier Quinn)", October, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Robertsonianism Redivivus", November, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Some Implications of Chaucer's Folktales" (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Francis Lee Utley, "Stylistic Ambivalence in Chaucer, Yeats and Lucretius- The Cresting Wave and Its Undertow", March, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Eugéne Vinaver, "From Epic to Romance", March, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Eugéne Vinaver, "La Fee Morgain Et Les Aventures de Bretagne" (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Eugéne Vinaver, "La mort de Roland", April-June, 1964, 2 copies (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Eugéne Vinaver, "Principles of Textual Emendation" (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Eugéne Vinaver, "A Speech Made by the President of the International Arthurian Society" (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Arnold Williams, "The 'Limitour' of Chaucer's Time and His 'Limitacioun,'", July, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Arnold Williams, "Two Notes on Chaucer's Friars", November, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Marion Witt, "The Vision of a Whole People: Yeat's Byzantium", May 8, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Karl Young, "The Dit de la Harpe of Guillaume de Machaut" (Box 9, Folder 65)